

Rangareddy, India 500075



sandeepsirisinagandla@gmail.

Data enthusiast with 6.5 years of dedicated experience in in business intelligence and reporting, specializing in Qlik. I possess strong capabilities in Qlik designing and development, ensuring robust and efficient solutions. Known for my rapid learning abilities and adeptness at quickly mastering new tools and technologies, I excel in implementing them in real-time to deliver effective solutions. My comprehensive skill set in Qlik development and support guarantees consistent and highquality maintenance postdevelopment.

#### **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

- Explore new things like tools, technologies and finding new improvement methods
- Reading newspaper, magazines and watching television news
- Cooking

# SANDEEP BABU SIRISINAGANDLA

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Enhancing new skills, tools and technologies.** Looking for a new role.

07/2022 - Current

Continuously developed capabilities in various areas by staying up to date with the latest advancements in my field. New learnings:

- 1. Alteryx
- 2. Data Engineering
- 3. Resume projects

# **Senior Consultant (Qlik)** HSBC (Capgemini - FTE) 04/2021 - 07/2022

- Prepared Qlik Sense apps, analyzed JSON data of various IT Projects from JIRA system
- Technology used in project: Qlik Sense, JIRA
- Description: HSBC banking Qlik team is automating all its service apps data into Qlik Sense application and named the project as "Ops Tooling" & RADAR project.

# **Senior Consultant (Qlik)** Becton Dickinson (Capgemini - FTE) 02/2020 - 03/2021

- Handled EMEA Qlik Sense ServiceNow tickets and incidents related to 38 Qlik Sense applications. Performed maintenance tasks like cleaning up Sheets, inactive users, objects, and images. Monitored QMC Daily app reloads and NPrinting report distributions.
- Technology used in project: Qlik Sense, SQL Server
- Description: Becton Dickinson BI platform has many BI tools
- Qlik is one of the tools to monitor the sales, finances, daily sales, and other service apps
- There are 38 EMEA Qlik apps to assist wide user group to monitor the health and perform decision-making.

# Senior Consultant (Qlik) Novo Nordisk (Capgemini - FTE) 11/2019 - 01/2020

- Developed ad-hoc Qlik reports to analyze and validate Novo Nordisk's systems and servers data, including data validation against spreadsheets and test case preparation.
- Technology used in project: Qlik Sense
- Description: Novo Nordisk is a leading pharma company that produces diabetic solutions
- Analysis of its systems and servers data using Qlik Sense
- Analyzed and developed Splunk and windows server system data in Qlik Sense.

# **Senior Consultant (Qlik)** Syngenta (Capgemini - FTE) 10/2019 - 10/2019

 Designed and implemented custom Qlik reports to efficiently identify and confirm anomalies in Market/Sales Data for Syngenta, validated by testing against SQL Server database.

- Technology used in project: QlikView, Windows server 2012 R2, SQL Server
- Description: Syngenta is a leading agri-business produces and sells many Agri-Products
- Development and analysis its sales data is being done in QlikView Reporting system.

### **Senior Software Engineer (Qlik)** Citi Bank (LTI - FTE) 09/2018 - 05/2019

- Developed ad hoc Qlik reports to validate Markets AML
  Data exceptions for Citi Bank against oracle database and prepared test cases.
- Technology used in project: QlikView, SQL
- Markets AML Tech conducts checks on exceptions and generates JIRA tickets for failed exceptions.
- Markets AML dashboards display visualizations of AML exceptions, JIRAs, Business Analysts.

# **Senior Software Engineer (Qlik)** Orchid Underwriter's LLC (LTI - FTE)

03/2018 - 09/2018

- Led requirement gathering sessions and estimated project scope. Prepared comprehensive design document showcasing development techniques. Developed applications using both waterfall and agile methodologies. Executed SQL queries and prepared datasets for Qlik visualization.
- Technology used in project: QlikView, Oracle Database
- Description: Orchid Underwriter's LLC Orchid Dashboard is a Qlik application that shows Insurance metrics of Orchid Underwriters LLC.

# Senior Software Engineer Eaton (LTI - FTE) 07/2017 - 03/2018

- Collected project requirements, estimated project scope, and developed design documentation to outline utilized development techniques.
- Technology used in project: QlikView, Flat-Files
- Description: Eaton's IT Allocations Dashboard is a Qlik application that shows telephone expenses allocation for IT projects across globe.

### Senior Software Engineer OTIS (LTI - FTE) 02/2017 - 07/2017

- Designed and developed AR applications, including ad hoc features and UI/backend enhancements. Supported day-to-day tasks such as monitoring, access requests, migrations etc. Utilized SQL Server for querying and data set preparation necessary for Qlik.
- Technology used in project: QlikView, Windows Server 2012 R2, SQL Server 2012
- Managed the development of multiple finance applications such as Accounts Receivables, Accounts Payables, and Service App as part of the Qlik finance project at OTIS Global BI.

### Senior Consultant Wipro Technologies - (Payroll Co: Adecco - Contractual Role) 08/2016 - 11/2016

- Fixed bugs and enhanced UI, ad hoc designed and developed applications, Improved UI and backend functionality.
- Technology used in project: QlikView & QMC, SQL Server 2012, Windows Server 2012 R2

- Managed TOBI, a BI project for Shire Pharma, including two sub-projects focused on rare diseases and supply chain dashboards.
- Explained rare diseases and global ailments, as well as supply chain project metrics and KPIs for Shire Pharma.

Senior Software Engineer CA Technologies - (Payroll Co: ISS SOFTWARE PVT LTD - Contractual Role) 05/2016 - 05/2016

- Built proto-types, conducted Support Model KT and identified root causes of bookmark issues.
- Technology used in project: QlikView & QMC, Windows Server 2012 R2, SQL Server 2008
- Description: FY16 Application Cloud Migrati has a metrics dashboard for BI team of CA technologies that explains metrics and KPIs of Qlik & BO service tickets.

Senior Consultant Enzen Technologies - (Payroll Co: SmartEdge Technologies - Contractual Role) 10/2014 - 07/2015

- Developed QlikView apps for finance, customer satisfaction, and energy efficiency.
- Technology used in project: QlikView, SAP
- Managed BI Industrialization project focused on metrics and KPIs of Wales and West Utilities, a UK-based utilities company
- Analyzed metrics and KPIs for Customer Satisfaction and Ops Productivity.

Data Analyst Teamware Solutions Private Limited 06/2013 - 09/2013

- Excel Reporting for daily PMO activities and estimation of hiring pay cycle
- Tools Used: MS Excel & SharePoint (End user only)

Global Fin Ops Analyst (FTE) Amazon India Private Limited 01/2011 - 05/2013

- Collaborated with Amazon sellers to facilitate their routine business functions, focusing on email-based interactions.
- Functioned as a Global Fin Ops Analyst, aiding Amazon vendors with their daily procurement activities through email
- Tools Used: MS Excel & Amazons Proprietary Software

#### Customer Service Executive (FTE) HSBC 06/2010 - 12/2010

- Aided HSBC Employees (USA & Canada) with their leave of absence inquiries through responsive communication channels including email and phone, during my tenure as a Customer Service Executive at HSBC.
- Tools Used: Proprietary & MS Office

### Process Associate (FTE) Genpact

07/2009 - 05/2010

- Processed invoices for Hyatt group of hotels, ensuring accuracy and timely payments
- Tools Used: Proprietary & MS Office

### **SKILLS**

- QlikView (Designing, Development & Deployment)
- Qlik Sense (Designing, Development & Deployment)

- SQL (Querying)
- Alteryx (Workflow Development)
- Data Engineering (AWS)
- MS Excel
- Metrics & KPIs
- Business English
- Client-facing experience
- Basic business statistics

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**NIIT DJVT (2013)** 

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Business Administration: Tax Procedures and Practices

Vivekavardhani Degree & PG College - Kottagudem, AP, 2007

- Coursework in Tax Procedures and Practices (Direct & Indirect Taxes - Indian Taxation)
- Bachelor of Commerce Graduate (Actual Degree)
- College: Vivekavardhani Degree & PG College (Kothagudem - Telangana State, India) affiliated to Kakatiya University.
- First Division (68.93%)

#### MARITAL STATUS

Single

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Title: Senior Consultant

Date of birth: 04/12/87

Gender: Male

Nationality: Indian

### **LANGUAGES**

Telugu: First Language

English: C1 Hindi:

Advanced Upper Intermediate

B2

### TRAINING

Qlik Sense, SQL & Alteryx (Fundamentals)

#### + PROJECTS

Developed Qlik Sense resume projects from Open data. Please download from GitHub repository:

https://github.com/sandeeps87/my\_qlik\_sense\_projects Udemy Certificates:

https://github.com/sandeeps87/udemycertificates